<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CVE on Kernels and Cats</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cve/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CVE on Kernels and Cats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Dive into Faronics Deep Freeze Enterprise [Legacy Windows Software]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/faronics-deep-freeze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/faronics-deep-freeze/</guid>
      <description>TLDR Faronics Deep Freeze Enterprise version 8.38.220.5256 is vulnerable to a stack buffer overflow vulnerability. It uses 2 XOR encoding schemes, as well as an additional third checksum, to ensure that the packets sent to it are valid. As DEP is enabled, the stack buffer overflow can be exploited by building a ROP chain with a dummy VirtualAlloc skeleton, patching the arguments in, and performing a stack pivot to call VirtualAlloc and finally return to our shellcode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nftables Adventures: CVE-2023-31248 -- Oh How The Turn Tables! [Part 2]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/nftables-adventures-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/nftables-adventures-2/</guid>
      <description>TLDR CVE-2023-31248 is an n-day bug affecting nftables reported by Mingi Cho. The bug report and patch can be found here: https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=515ad530795c118f012539ed76d02bacfd426d89. Linux kernel versions before 6.2.0-26 generic are vulnerable to this bug. My exploit has been tested on Ubuntu 23.04 (Lunar Lobster), with kernel version 6.2.0-20 generic.&#xA;The official version of this writeup can be found at this link: https://starlabs.sg/blog/2023/09-nftables-adventures-bug-hunting-and-n-day-exploitation/&#xA;nfTable of Contents Vulnerability Analysis Triggering the Bug Obtaining a Use-After-Free Obtaining a Kernel Text Leak Obtaining a Heap Leak Controlling RIP Patch Analysis Exploit Demo Acknowledgements References and Credits Vulnerability Analysis nft_chain_lookup_byid does not check whether a chain is active (by checking the genmask) when looking up a chain, as seen in the code below:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
